let's start off by talking about your
daily routine tell me about your daily
routine okay well I wake up around 8
a.m. uh every morning it's like
clockwork and I brush my teeth I wash my
face breakfast um and then I get in my
car and I drive to work and uh yeah
that's basically it I come back home and
uh fix myself up some dinner and watch
on Netflix very average mundane how has
your daily routine changed since you
were a child not much except I go to
work now instead of school um but uh I
get a lot of free time over the weekends
so I get to do the things I like to do
such as meditation and writing I love
journaling I'd love to put out some
novels one day um I always thought that
I would retire to the countryside in my
old age with my animals and write books
so yeah so
writing
yoga what else do I do on the weekends
oh I want to try horse riding as well is
your daily routine different at the
weekend compared to during the week yes
100% so uh the weekday are for work
mainly being productive paying the bills
and the weekends I get to do whatever I
want to do so really treasure and enjoy
my weekends let's talk now about dreams
do you dream much at night I do dream
sometimes but not very often and when I
do dream I don't tend to remember my
dreams do you think we can learn
anything from dreams I think so I think
there's lots of repressed emotions and
stress that come out um during our
dreams uh that perhaps we haven't
addressed in real life so yes I I
believe we can learn quite a lot and I
suppose some people can even you know
predict the future through dreams or
images that they see I'm kind of on the
fence about that I don't know
but seems credible now let's talk about
email what kind of emails do you receive
about your work I receive a lot of
emails from my hups so my manager people
from other departments as well usually
following up for things
um or scheduling meetings um just a lot
of work that needs to be done and
reminders to please do this work so do
you normally reply to emails as soon as
you receive them oh
no um I don't because I feel like
there's no point in replying if the work
hasn't been done so let's say we're
supposed to schedule a meeting and
something needs to be done I'd much
prefer to get that thing done and then
respond by saying okay here it is here's
the file that you um that you requested
and that you asked for and um yeah
instead of you know a random sort of
hello well received thank you are you
happy to receive emails that are
advertising things no I don't think
anyone would be unless it's for a brand
that I follow or that I like unless
they're having a
sale um in that case I'd be more than
happy to receive their emails now let's
talk about exercise how often do you
exercise not as often as I would like I
find the gym to be quite tedious and
boring I prefer doing classes but then
to get myself to the class and sit
through traffic coming back so I would
love to work out a bit more frequently
and I I tend to like
slower exercises such as yoga or
swimming something where I don't really
have to break a sweat which is not very
um realistic but yeah what do you think
is the best exercise to keep fit um I've
tried Pilates I think it's really good
for toning the the body and the
muscles and you see a big difference it
might not burn as many calories but you
do see a huge difference in your
silhouette so have the types of exercise
people like to do changed since you were
a child I would say not really the types
of exercises that people do I would say
they just don't exercise as much perhaps
it's gone from cycling and Tennis to
dancing on Tik Tok I think that would be
the main difference if I'm really honest
describe a time when you enjoyed
visiting a family member or friends I
went back to
Taiwan uh last month and I stayed for
about 3 weeks I was visiting friends and
family um but uh I don't really have
much family in Taiwan just my mom so
I've noticed that you know in life when
you don't have a lot of family the
universe brings you friends and it might
sound a bit cliche but friends really
are the family that you know you've
chosen and so I've now moved away from
Taiwan but when I was there made a lot
of very very good I think lifelong
friends who I go back and visit
periodically I visited Shirley I've been
friends with her since I was 15 so so
that's about 15 years now so you can
guess my age um Tiffany I've known her
since I was 18 um sill Eva so I visited
these friends in particular we just
pretty much not to sound boring we just
hung out and talked a lot caught up a
lot on life what's been happening who
are you dating you know are you happy so
there was a lot of that over wine or tea
and um I also went and visited sir's new
uh
restaurant and he's been doing really
really well for himself I'm very happy
about that we went and visited um Jackie
and um found out that he was actually
also back in Taiwan for his wedding so
he went to his wedding had a bit too
much whiskey but that's okay we won't
repeat that experience um it was fun in
in general it was it was a lot of fun um
it it was lovely to see Tiffany and Eva
because they both had babies during the
past one or two years and it was lovely
to see them yeah so we've been talking
about people that you visited and we're
going to continue to talk about family
when do families celebrate together in
your
country to thank you for watching this
video I want to give you a free course
that has helped thousands of students
improve their I speaking score what it's
going to do is take you through every
single part of the test and give you
strategies for part one part two and
part three and also allow you to
practice at home for free and get
feedback to sign up for that for free
all you have to do is just click the
link in the description thanks very much
and let's get back to the video Chinese
New Year that's a big
one uh the mid- Autumn Festival that's
also a big one any celebration really is
an excuse for the family to get together
which can be a bit stressful at times
because we all know how we feel about
our families we love them but it's sort
of a LoveHate relationship CU they can
get on our no sometimes but oh
well why is it that some people might
not enjoy attending family gatherings I
think because you know relatives
especially get it in their heads that
their family and so they think they can
ask any questions you know when are you
going to get married that's a big one
when are you going to have a baby while
you wasting your time so that that can
be a bit stressful because the whole
point of you
know being on vacation cuz now to see my
family I have to go on vacation and go
back to my country to see them is to
relax uh not to get stressed out so I
think a lot of people have the same
experience now let's talk about everyday
life in families do you think it is a
good thing for parents to help their
children with their homework yes I think
it's a very good thing I think it's
important to
have your mom or your dad present in
your childhood it's very good for mental
health so you don't need to see a
therapist when you grow up how important
do you think it is for families to eat
dinner together oh very very very
important it's important to feel that
connection because you could be people
living in the same house if you don't
communicate regularly interact regularly
what's the point of having a family
what's the point of having you know your
parents around then if they're not going
to be parents do you believe that
everyone in a family should share chores
yes I think so I think uh that's very
important however let's say if Dad is
out working most of the week then maybe
he doesn't need to do as many chores I
know it might sound a bit sexist but
it's really about um um what's the word
Distributing work evenly I'm now going
to give you some feedback on your
performance so we're going to break the
feedback down into uh part one part two
and part three and then I'm going to
give you some band scores and your
scores for pronunciation fluency grammar
and vocabulary so thank you for making
it this far in the video I want to give
you 10% off our VIP course I VIP course
is the most successful I course in the
world that is a fact because we have
more band seven8 and N success stories
than any other I course in the entire
world we do that by simplifying the
whole is process supporting you with
some of the best is teachers in the
world and being with you every step of
the way until you get the score that you
need all you have to do is just look
down in the description just click that
and you can sign up if you have any
questions about the VIP course always
feel free to get in touch with us we
answer 100% of the questions that we get
hope that you would become a VIP if not
enjoy the rest of this free video part
one you did a great job with part one it
was like talking to a colleague talking
to a friend um you didn't really have to
think much about the answers you didn't
really have to think about the language
you were using it was all very very
natural one thing I don't think this is
going to be a huge issue for you um but
sometimes under pressure on exam day
some students do this and you do it a
little bit which is you list like lots
of things if you did that with too many
answers you're indicating to The
Examiner I don't really know how to
construct a sentence exactly exactly so
it is much better to pick one or two
things and go deep on those things
rather than go wide so going wide is
just you know what's your favorite food
I like pizza I like burgers I like sushi
I like Thai I like it's better to pick
one of those I like taii because and
explain why that is so that allows you
to really show off your grammar show off
your vocabulary because your grammar and
vocabulary is amazing we want to show
that to the examiner I don't think it's
going to be an issue for you but as I
said some people when they're practicing
um do amazingly well and then as soon as
you I call it test mode as soon as they
get going to the test they start to do
these little weird things that are kind
of defensive um for someone like you we
don't want you to be defensive we want
to show how how good you are part two
you had no problem talking about that
you could have talked about that for
many more minutes than than two minutes
um and I have no no feedback on that
it's just it was really really good part
three you did develop your answers
probably enough but you could have
developed them a little bit more you
could have possibly shown the other side
of things you you talked about
everything kind of from a personal point
of view which is good because it's
you're very fluent when you do that just
remember part three is a discussion of
ideas so it's good to think well I
really think this but I can sort of see
why other people would think this way um
so for example do you think it's a good
idea for parents to help children with
their school work now that's pretty
obvious that yes that's a good thing but
you could say something like however I
understand that some moms and dads are
really busy and and they don't have time
to do that I don't agree with that but I
can understand why why is it that some
people might not enjoy attending family
occasions you gave a very straight
answer which was very very
good but you could have maybe well
that's what I feel but maybe there's
this other reason why people um you
don't need to list you know five
different reasons but maybe say but some
people might not have these issues
perhaps yeah yeah or something like that
pronunciation you would get a band nine
which is the top band because you're
your pronun ation is is perfect um not
just accent so a lot of people watching
this video will listen to you and think
oh she has a beautiful British accent
and that is something that people can
strive for but they don't need a
particular type of British accent to do
well you could have a Taiwanese accent
an Indian accent a Vietnamese accent and
still get a band nine it's more about
the clarity of your accent rather than
the type of accent that you have now you
do have
one of those very uh admired accents for
people on our channel so people will be
very impressed with that but people
watching shouldn't think I need to sign
more British um because it's not a it's
not a British RP test it is a you know
it is a an English test Clarity I
understood 100% of what you were saying
and then you also have very high level
pronunciation features such as
intonation so you show meaning and humor
and things like that through intonation
you also show that through um sentence
stress so sentence stress is like this
is my phone this isn't your phone so you
emphasize certain words to display
meaning your connected speech is great
so if somebody's learning they might say
do you want to go to the coffee shop so
everything is perfectly clear but how
you would say it do you want to go to
the coffee shop do you want to go so it
signs kind of like one continuous a sign
or word so band nine for pronunciation
coherence and fluency are in the same
band and you get whatever is lowest so
if your coherence is band eight and your
fluency is band nine you get a band
eight and vice versa your fluency is
perfect if you listen to someone who is
learning English their fluency suffers
because they're trying to fetch the
correct word or the correct phrase or
should I use past simple or present
perfect you don't have any issues with
that and you don't have any issues with
ideas and information you're just
without effort your coherence coherence
is did you answer the question and did
you develop it enough you did but we
need to be careful with that if you did
the real test because as I said your
fluency could be perfect but you're not
developing your answers enough which
could drag you down I don't think it
would but we need to out of abundance of
of caution grammar I didn't hear a
single grammar mistake
so the examiner will be thinking about
accuracy did she make any mistakes and
range does she have enough tenses enough
grammatical structures to talk about the
things that she wants to talk about so
for example I asked you about how is
exercise change since you were a child
that requires you to use past simple
present perfect things like that you had
no problem with that whatsoever so b
nine for grammar b nine for vocabulary
as well because you used amazing
idiomatic vocabulary like this a native
English speaker will use idiomatic
phrases which are phrases that Learners
don't really know how to use you only
really know how to use them if you grew
up in an English speaking country or you
got to a very very high level of English
vocabulary is very precise and accurate
and you have a huge range of vocabulary
you could talk about any topic that I
could throw at you so b n all all across
the board thank you which is extremely
rare uh less than 1% of people get
upline oh wow okay well thank you very
much I'll work on my coherence it is
true I tend to think out loud so maybe
it's not coherent in that sense because
I'm just basically listing in my head
yeah yeah good thank you very much thank
you